Good news guys, I did become an American
citizen back in 2016, so I'm one of you
guys now.
Thank [cheering] you.
>> [applause]
>> Thank you. Yeah, it was great.
Yeah. And to get my citizenship, I had
to go down to the center, get my test,
right? And the lady giving me my test
was this older lady from Mexico, and she
had a very heavy Mexican accent still.
And we did the test, I finished the
written portion, and then she said, "Now
it's time for the English proficiency
part of the test."
And I said, "Hey, let's stop right
there. I think we can both agree that
you're doing great." That's all I was
That's the story how I almost did not
become an American citizen, guys. It's
uh
I got to learn how to keep my mouth
shut.
Uh but the best part about being
American, honestly, is that you guys win
everything. I love being part of that.
That's
Woo! All right?
The Olympics recently, we crushed it
again at the Olympics, like first place
for like the 50th year in a row or
something.
>> [laughter]
>> But the best part about the Olympics
this year for me was the Australian
breakdancers. She was That's fine.
That was horrible. That was
>> [laughter]
>> And when I was watching her, I thought
to myself, "Wow, Make-A-Wish is killing
it this year. Oh my gosh."
I had no idea you wish for the Olympics.
>> [laughter]
>> I thought you were limited to asking
like retired wrestlers to visit you in
the hospital. This is incredible.
And then when she got all that bad
feedback after that performance, I
thought to myself, "The happiest person
right now in the world is that person
who finished second place in Australia."
You know what I mean?
Yeah, she dodged a bullet there. That's
But we win everything. Here's a true
story. I found that the US also just
beat China in the math Olympics, guys.
True story. Yes.
Yes, guys, give it up for the winners
from California, Jason Chang and Ling
Ling Wong.
>> [laughter]
[applause and cheering]
>> Huh?
That's right. Bringing home the gold for
the US, you guys.
>> [laughter]
>> We taught China a powerful powerful
lesson, didn't we?
>> [laughter]
>> Yeah, now they know exactly what makes
America great.
>> [laughter]
>> They interviewed the parents and the
winners, and the parents they were
really proud of our kids. We hope they
go on to do great things. I mean, that's
what the translator said. I don't know.
I don't speak Chinese myself.
Uh if you are still curious and you're
wondering, I am actually Vietnamese. And
if you don't have a good grasp of
history or geography,
I'm Chinese, whatever. That's fine.
>> [laughter]
>> I'll be Chinese for 35 more minutes for
you. It's fine.
I know you can't tell. It's okay. I uh
No. Oh, hey, before I forget, I want to
make sure am I coming through okay? You
understand me okay? Yeah? Awesome. Cool.
The reason I asked is because English is
actually my second language, and I'm a
little embarrassed to say this, but even
after all these years here, I still
sometimes get a little confused by how
poorly you speak it. So, bear with me.
>> [laughter]
>> If you need me to slow down or use
smaller words, let me know. I can
accommodate everybody.
>> [laughter]
>> But I'm from Vietnam. My parents brought
me over after the war in Vietnam, and
I'll always be grateful to them for
that. If I stayed in Vietnam, like who
knows what would have happened, right? I
might have ended up working in a
sweatshop, you know, working horrible
hours for terrible terrible people. But
instead, with my parents' love and
support, I got a chance to go to law
school, and then I got a job in a big
law firm afterwards, where I work
horrible hours for terrible terrible
people.
>> [laughter]
>> Yeah, I couldn't really escape my fate
on that one, guys.
>> [laughter]
>> Fighting my destiny too hard there. Too
hard. I uh
But speaking of Asia, I was there
recently, guys. I was working out there
doing comedy as well. And uh in Asia, I
found out that the incidences of
kidnapping are among the lowest in the
world. Did you guys know this? Yeah, I
couldn't figure out why until I
remembered, that's right, you can't make
a good living kidnapping Asian kids. You
know what I mean? Because the only thing
Asian parents love more than their
children is a good bargain. You know
what I'm talking about? Like
>> [laughter]
>> The kid
The kidnappers will kidnap the child,
right? Call the parents like, "Listen,
we got your kid. You want to see him
again? You pay us a million dollars."
And the parents like, "Whoa, stop. Hang
on a second.
What's your best offer? What are we
talking about here? What are we Being
realistic, right? Can you imagine being
that kid and listening to your parents
negotiate your life down to the lowest
dollar?
>> [laughter]
>> And you know your parents, they're going
to call their friends to brag. They're
going to ring them up.
"The kidnappers wanted a million
dollars. We got him back for $300.
It's incredible. [laughter]
What did you pay? A thousand? Terrible
deal. That's terrible. Call us next
time."
But I traveled around Asia, did comedy.
I was in the Philippines doing comedy
out there. I don't know if Do we have
Filipino people here today?
Yeah? Awesome. My Filipino fans, you
guys made it this far north. Awesome.
>> [laughter]
>> It's crazy. I love my Filipino friends,
but I love teasing you guys by telling
you you're not really Asian. They hate
that so much.
Yeah, you guys get so mad. You're like,
"Oh, we're Asian." And I'm always like,
"All right, just calm down there, Jose
Dela Cruz." I'm just saying.
I'm just saying, if white people can
pronounce your name,
>> [laughter]
>> how Asian are you? You know?
Filipinos, you confuse me, you guys. On
the one hand, you don't use chopsticks.
On the other hand, you love karaoke.
Pick a side, guys. Pick a side.
>> [laughter]
>> I spent most of my time in Singapore
though when I was in Asia, my home base
there. Met a lot of Indians in
Singapore. I didn't know there's a huge
population of Indians there, and I met
them. They're so successful. All the
ones I met were really successful. I
have no idea why Indians are so
successful when they spend so much time
at weddings every year. You know what
I'm talking about? Like
They spend 150 days a year at weddings,
and they still run Microsoft and Google.
It's unbelievable.
>> [laughter]
>> I think that's why Indian marriages last
so long is because they spent 4 years
just getting married. You know what I
mean? Like They're like, "What's another
50? Let's keep going, you know?"
But Singapore is a great place to be.
It's a very safe country. Do you guys
know about the safety in Singapore? It's
a very safe country. Uh it's got a
reputation for that, and I I I I found
that out cuz I read a story about a
crime in Singapore that made the papers
one day. It was about two guys who got
into a road rage incident. They got out
of the cars, they started yelling at
each other.
And that was it. the whole story. That
was crime in Singapore.
I was like, "That made the papers?"
They're like, "Yeah." Right? Even the
way they prevent crime in Singapore is
very gentle, right? I was on the subway,
they had a poster with a slogan that
said, "If you molest, we will arrest."
They took a very serious crime, and they
made it adorable. You know what I'm
talking about? Like
>> [laughter]
>> The police in Singapore are sitting
around one day like, "How do we prevent
assaults on our subway?" And one guy
raised his hand. He's like, "I have an
idea.
Nursery rhymes. We're going to do
nursery rhymes. It's going to be
amazing.
Stop crime.
If you molest, we will arrest."
That probably wasn't the first draft of
that slogan, right? The first draft was
probably something different. It's
probably like, "If you harass, we cane
your" I'm not a poet, guys. I'm not a
poet.
>> [laughter]
>> I'm bad with rhymes. You guys finish
that one up. I uh
No, but Singapore is an interesting
place. I think the government in
Singapore knows it's a very safe place
as well. I think you can tell they know
by the people they hire for subway
security. Have you guys been to
Singapore? Have you seen these
75-year-old aunties and uncles that they
hire for subway security? What happens
in Singapore is when you get too old to
feed the pigeons, you get a job as
subway security there.
Right?
And they give you a little cart, and
there's a sign up top that says
"Security Checkpoint." And when I first
got to Singapore, I used to stop at the
security checkpoint until I realized one
day, if I just walk a little faster,
they can't catch me. You know what I
mean? Like just
>> [laughter]
>> They're not going to risk breaking a hip
to find out if I got gum in my backpack,
you know?
But I found a lot of cool things about
Singapore when I was there. My friends
told me that in Singapore, you can't
actually buy a house from the government
until you get married. You guys know
this? And then when you have a baby in
Singapore, the government gives you cash
money. It's unbelievable. The
Singaporean government treats their
citizens like pandas. You know what I'm
talking about? Like they're just like,
"Please, reproduce. We need more of
you."